Guide to the Irving Fisher Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- MICROFILM INVENTORY
  - Economic Essays, Vol. V: "Standardizing the Dollar", to 1913 June 1
    - Newspapers
      - Extract, speech, A. E. A., Boston Meeting, 1912 (Box 2)
      - Letter to the News, Indianapolis, 1913 (Box 2)
      - Extract, address, Western N[ew] E[ngland] Cham[ber of] Com[merce], 1913 (Box 2)
      - Letter to Globe, Toronto, 1913 (Box 2)
      - Letter to News, Indianapolis, 1913 (Box 2)
      - Letter to the News Scimitar, Memphis, 1913 (Box 2)
      - Extract, speech, Friendship League, Phila., 1913 (Box 2)
      - Extract, Bristol Business Men's Assoc., 1913 (Box 2)
      - Letter to Pearson's Magazine, 1913 (Box 2)
      - Letter to Evening Journal, Albany, 1913 (Box 2)
      - Extract Picayune, New Orleans, 1913 (Box 2)
      - Letter to New York Times (answering Frewen), 1913 (Box 2)
      - Letter to Wall Street Journal, 1913 (Box 2)
      - Extract, speech, 20th Century Club, Worcester, 1913 (Box 2)
      - Letter, Jour[nal] of Com[merce] (in re income tax), 1913 (Box 2)
      - Letter to Phil. Record, 1913 (Box 2)
      - Comments and Endorsements, 1912 (Box 2)
  - Economic Essays, Vol. VI: "General Economics", 1913 June 1 - 1918 January 1
    - General Publications
      - Standardization of the Dollar as a Remedy for Fluctuating Prices, Introduction to Great American Debates, 1913 (Box 2)
      - Summary of Statement sent to Glass Committee on Banking and Currency, 1913 (Box 2)
      - Statement before Committee on Banking and Currency, 1913 (Box 2)
      - Letter correcting editorial quoting currency views ( N.Y. World ), 1913 (Box 2)
      - Interview on Currency Bill ( N.H. Register ), 1913 (Box 2)
      - Preliminary "Equation of Exchange" for 1913 and Forecast ( Amer[ican] Economic Rev[iew] ), 1914 (Box 2)
      - The Equation of Exchange for 1913 and Forecast ( Amer. Economic Review ), 1914 (Box 2)
      - Suggested Problems for Use with Elementary Principles of Economics, Second Edition, 1914 (Box 2)
      - Address at Socialist Hall ( N.H. Union ), 1914 (Box 2)
      - Review of "Recherches sur La Theorie du Prix" by Rudolph Auspitz and Richard Lieben ( Amer. Economic Review ), 1915 (Box 2)
      - The Equation of Exchange for 1914 and the War ( Amer[ican] Economic Review ), 1915 (Box 2)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1915 (Box 2)
      - Interview on Proposed Change in Income Tax ( N.H. Register ), 1915 (Box 2)
      - Some Impending National Problems ( Journal of Political Economy ), 1916 (Box 2)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1916 (Box 2)
      - The Equation of Exchange for 1915 ( Amer. Economic Review ), 1916 (Box 2)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1916 (Box 2)
      - The Rate of Interest After the War ( Annals of the Amer. Academy of Political and Social Science ), 1916 (Box 2)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1916 (Box 2)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1916 (Box 2)
        - Extract from same ( Economic World, N.Y.), 1916 (Box 2)
        - Article based on same ( American Banker, N.Y.), 1916 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same ( The Chronicle ), 1916 (Box 2)
      - Discussion of Professor Hollander's paper ( Amer. Economic Review Supplement ), 1916 (Box 2)
      - A Multi-Billion Dollar Nation ( The Annalist ,New York), 1916 (Box 2)
      - Over and Under Counting ( The Annalist ), 1916 (Box 2)
      - Plotting Ratios along with Amounts ( The Annalist ), 1917 (Box 2)
      - Taxation vs. Bonds as a Means of Financing War ( The Annalist ), 1917 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same ( Literary Digest ), 1917 (Box 2)
      - Use of Income Tax Statistics ( Bulletin of the National Tax Association ), 1917 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same for distribution, 1917 (Box 2)
      - The "Ratio" Chart for Plotting Statistics ( Quarterly Publication of the Amer. Statistical Assoc. ), 1917 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same, 1917 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same ( Efficiency Society Jour[nal] ), 1917 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same ( The Annalist ), 1917 (Box 2)
      - The Equation of Exchange for 1916 ( Amer. Economic Review ), 1917 (Box 2)
      - Statement issued thru the Natl. Emergency Food Garden Commission at Wash., D.C. ( Eagle, Brooklyn, N.Y.), 1917 (Box 2)
      - Extract from "Use of Income Tax Statistics" ( Inter Ocean, Chicago), 1917 (Box 2)
        - Extract from same ( Press, Pittsburgh), 1917 (Box 2)
      - Article based on "Rate of Interest After the War" ( Journal Gazette, Fort Wayne, Ind.), 1917 (Box 2)
      - Address before Portland Realty Board ( Oregonian, Portland), 1917 (Box 2)
    - Economic effects of the war
      - Some Probable Economic Effects of the War ( New York Times ), 1914 (Box 2)
        - Extract from same ( The Optimist, Cincinnati), 1914 (Box 2)
      - Reprint of Addendum to "Why is the Dollar Shrinking?" ( Moody's Magazine ), 1914 (Box 2)
      - Interview ( Journal-Courier ), N.H., 1914 (Box 2)
      - Deflation after the War ( Boston News Bur. ), 1916 (Box 2)
      - Opinion on Conditions Likely to Obtain after the War ( Natl. Econ. League Quart. ), 1916 (Box 2)
    - Publications contained in other forms in previous volumes
      - Over-Capitalization Deceitful ( Journal of Acountancy ), 1907
      - Capital and Interest, reprint, 1909
      - Recent Changes in Price Levels and Their Causes, original with discussion, 1911
        See also: Vol. III, series 7, reel 1, volume 3
      - Extract from Preliminary "Equation of Exchange" for 1912 and Forecast ( Amer. Economic Review ), 1913
      - The Equation of Exchange for 1912 and Forecast, 1913
    - Early publications omitted from previous volumes
      - English Views on Bimetallism ( New York Evening Post ), 1895 (Box 2)
      - Review of "Pure Economics" by Professor Maffeo Pantaleoni, 1898 (Box 2)
      - Review of "The Chances of Death and Other Studies in Evolution" by Karl Pearson ( Yale Review ), 1898 (Box 2)
  - Economic Essays, Vol. VII: "General Economics", 1918 January 1 - 1921 December 31
    - General publications
      - Is "Utility" the Most Suitable Term for the Concept it is Used to Denote? ( American Economic Review ), 1918 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same, 1918 (Box 2)
      - Letter to Providence Journal on "Gold Production" ( Journal, Providence), 1918 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of above letter ( Monthly Market Letter, Goodbody & Co.), 1918 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same ( Economic World ), 1918 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same ( Financial Age, 1918 (Box 2)
      - The Equation of Exchange for 1918 ( Amer. Economic Review ), 1919 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same, 1919 (Box 2)
      - Correspondence with Mr. Chester T. Kennan in re Gold ( Northwest Mining Truth ), 1919 (Box 2)
      - Money and Credit, published by Amer. Institute of Finance as part of their service, 1920 (Box 2)
      - Letter: Lenine's Golden Goose, to N.Y. Herald re question of U.S. opening commercial relations with Soviet Russia, 1921 (Box 2)
      - Statement re Amer. Valuation Plan written for Amer. Valuation Committee ( N.Y. Times ), 1921 (Box 2)
    - Economists in Public Service
      - Economists in Public Service, advance reprint from American Economic Review, 1918 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same, (2 items) ( N.Y. Tribune ), 1918 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same ( News, Newark), 1918 (Box 2)
      - Economists in Public Service ( American Economic Review ), 1919 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same, 1919 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same
          - The World Court, 1919 (Box 2)
          - N.Y. Tribune, (4 items), 1919 (Box 2)
          - Milwaukee Journal, 1919 (Box 2)
          - American Industries, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Post Express, Rochester, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Star, St. Louis, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Iron Age, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Christian Work, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Reedy's Mirror, 1919 (Box 2)
    - Economic effects of the war
      - Broadside of the first Report of the "Committee on the Purchasing Power of Money in Relation to the War" of the Amer. Economic Assoc., Treasury Dept. Publicity Bulletin, 1918 (Box 2)
      - Correspondence with Master Builders Assoc. re First Report, 1918 (Box 2)
      - Extracts from the First Report ( Official Bulletin ), 1918 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same
          - Commercial and Financial Chronicle, 1918 (Box 2)
          - N.Y. Tribune, 1918 (Box 2)
          - War-Thrift, 1918 (Box 2)
          - Albany Daily Democrat, 1918 (Box 2)
      - Some Contributions of the War to Our Knowledge of Money and Prices ( Amer. Econ. Review ), 1918 (Box 2)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1918 (Box 2)
      - Second Report of the "Committee on the Purchasing Power of Money in Relation to the War" ( Financial America ), 1918 (Box 2)
      - Third Report of the "Committee on the Purchasing Power of Money in Relation to the War" ( Hartford Times ), 1918 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same ( Old Colony NewsLetter ), 1918 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same ( Financier ), 1918 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same
          - Daily Iron Trade, 1918 (Box 2)
          - Business Chronicle of the Pacific Northwest, 1918 (Box 2)
          - War-Thrift, 1918 (Box 2)
      - The Right and Wrong Way of Financing the War ( Trust Companies ), 1918 (Box 2)
      - Quotation from conference with F.V. Dunham ( Star, Indianapolis), 1918 (Box 2)
      - How the Public Should Pay for the War ( Annals of American Academy of Political and Social Science ), 1918 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same ( N.Y. Commercial ), 1918 (Box 2)
      - Business as Usual vs. Save and Work ( Independent ), 1918 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same, 1918 (Box 2)
    - Industrial psychiatry
      - How Can the Employer Help the Worker Satisfy His Fundamental Human Instincts? (Desk card prepared for Y.M.C.A.), 1918 (Box 2)
      - Interview on "Labor" ( Hanover Gazette, Hanover, N.H.), 1919 (Box 2)
      - Humanizing Industry ( Annals of American Academy of Pol. & Social Science ), 1919 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same, 1919 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same
          - Evening Mail, N.Y., 1919 (Box 2)
          - Tribune, Minneapolis, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Tribune, Providence, R.I., 1919 (Box 2)
          - Herald, Bridgeport, Conn., 1919 (Box 2)
          - Evening Post, 1919 (Box 2)
          - News, Springfield, Ohio, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Review of Reviews, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Rural Manhood, 1919 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same ( N.J. Municipalities ), 1919 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same ( North American ), 1919 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same ( Soldiers, Sailors, Marines ), 1919 (Box 2)
      - Revised edition of Desk Card, 1919 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same ( Survey ), 1919 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same ( Knickerbocker Press ), 1919 (Box 2)
      - Reprint of Desk Card ( Personnel ), 1919 (Box 2)
      - Address before Economic Club of Boston ( The Consensus ), 1919 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same ( The Universalist Leader ), 1919 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same ( Boston Herald ), 1919 (Box 2)
      - Extracts from address before Economic Club of Boston ( Evening Transcript ), 1919 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same ( Herald ) Boston, 1919 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same ( Globe, Boston), 1919 (Box 2)
      - Extracts from address before Amer. Medical Assoc. on Labor as an After War Problem ( Press, Phila.), 1919 (Box 2)
    - Early publications omitted from previous volumes
      - Extracts from address based on add. before U. of N. Dak. at Mills College ( Christian Advocate ), 1917 (Box 2)
      - Extracts from talk on "Food Conservation" ( N.H. Register ), 1917 (Box 2)
      - Interview on Liberty Loans vs. Taxation ( Yale News ), 1917 (Box 2)
      - Address before members of Confidential Exchange ( Hartford Daily Times ), 1917 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same ( Hartford Courant ), 1917 (Box 2)
  - Economic Essays, Vol. VIII: "High Cost of Living", 1913 June 1 - 1920 January 1
    - General publications
      - Extract from Testimony before Bay State Street Railway Board, arbitration brief, 1914 (Box 2)
      - Quotations on High Cost of Living used in Arbitration Brief in Behalf of Div. 618 of Amalgamated Ass. of Street & Electric Railway Employees of America, 1915 (Box 2)
      - Extract from First Testimony before Bay State Street Railway Board ( The Journal, Boston), 1915 (Box 2)
      - Letter to Attorney Pelletier supplementing previous testimony before Board ( Post, Boston), 1915 (Box 2)
      - Letter to Editor correcting an article in regard to Testimony in Railway Case ( New Haven Union ), 1915 (Box 2)
      - Extract from Second Testimony before Bay State Street Railway Board ( Journal, Boston), 1915 (Box 2)
      - The Salaried Class and the Cost of Living ( Yale Alumni Weekly ), 1917 (Box 2)
      - Same--1st lecture (New York), 1918 (Box 2)
      - The New Price Revolution, read before Conf. of Governors and Mayors at White House ( U.S Department of Labor publ. ), 1919 (Box 2)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1919 (Box 2)
        - Separate reprint of same for distribution by Natl. Prosperity Campaign, 1919 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same
          - N.Y. Commercial, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Western Advertising, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Manufacturers Record, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Mount Hope Finishing Co., 1919 (Box 2)
          - Paper, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Mining and Scientific Press, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Tidskrift for Papirindustri, 1919 (Box 2)
          - The Shield, Indianapolis, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Hardware Dealer, N.Y.C., 1919 (Box 2)
          - Partial reprint Advertising and Selling, 1919 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same
          - Daily News Record, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Chicago Tribune, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Post, Washington, D.C., 1919 (Box 2)
          - N.Y. Tribune, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Courier, Poughkeepsie, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Evening News, Buffalo, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Manufacturer's New, Chi., 1919 (Box 2)
          - North American, Phila., 1919 (Box 2)
          - Real Estate Bulletin, N.Y., 1919 (Box 2)
          - Hotel Gazette, N.Y.C., 1919 (Box 2)
          - N.Y. Commercial, 1919 (Box 2)
          - News, Sault Ste Marie, Mich., 1919 (Box 2)
          - Christian Work, N.Y.C., 1919 (Box 2)
          - Courant, Phila., 1919 (Box 2)
          - Literary Digest, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Commerce and Finance, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Financial Age, N.Y.C., 1919 (Box 2)
          - Boston Herald, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Journal, Flint, Mich., 1919 (Box 2)
          - Economic World, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Times-Despatch [sic], Richmond, 1919 (Box 2)
          - British Columbia Financial Times, Vancouver, 1919 (Box 2)
          - New York Times - Real EstateSection, 1919 (Box 2)
        - Abstracts of same ( Observer, Utica, N.Y.), 1919 (Box 2)
        - Abstracts of same ( Scientific American ), 1919 (Box 2)
        - Quotation from same (Box 2)
          - Municipal & County Engineering, Chicago, 1919 (Box 2)
          - N.Y. Tribune, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Boston Evening Transcript, 1919 (Box 2)
          - New York Tribune, 1919 (Box 2)
          - New York Evening Post, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Public, New York, 1919 (Box 2)
      - Reconstruction and the Price Level, extracts from lecture in Lampson Lyceum based on The New Price Level ( North American, Philadelphia), 1919
        - Extracts from same
          - Hartford Courant, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Record, Meriden, Conn., 1919 (Box 2)
          - Yale Alumni Weekly, 1919 (Box 2)
      - Are Prices Coming Down? Based on The New Price Revolution ( Review of Reviews ), 1919 (Box 2)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1919 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same
          - Springfield Republican, 1919 (Box 2)
          - Evening Star News, Newark, N.J., 1919 (Box 2)
          - Evening Post, N.Y.C., 1919 (Box 2)
      - Future Prices of Money, Materials, and Equipment, reprint of paper read before the Second Hearing on Street Railways before the Public Utilities Com. of the Chamber of Commerce of the U.S., 1919
        - Extracts from same ( North American, Phila.), 1919 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same ( Electric Railway Journal ), 1919 (Box 2)
        - Abstract of same ( Electric Railway Journal ), 1919 (Box 2)
      - High Price Level Will Stay ( Magazine of Wall Street ), 1919 (Box 2)
      - Should Accept Situation ( Real Estate Magazine of New York ), 1920 (Box 2)
      - The War's Effect on the University's Income ( Yale Alumni Weekly ), 1920 (Box 2)
      - Prices Will Fall ( N.Y. Evening Sun ), 1920 (Box 2)
      - Gradual Rise in Price Level ( Yale News ), 1921 (Box 2)
      - The Business Outlook for 1921 ( Review of Reviews ) (Box 2)
      - Statement to Philadelphia Fair-Price Committee (( Public Ledger, Phila.), 1921 (Box 2)
      - Letter: "Prices and Money," replying to editorial in Times ( N.Y. Times ), 1921 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same ( American Artisan & Hardware Record, Chicago), 1921 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same ( Sales Management, Chi.), 1921 (Box 2)
        - Reply to Prof. Laughlin's comments on above ( N.Y. Times ), 1921 (Box 2)
      - Reclassification of Salaries, statement before Committees on Civil Service hearings relative to the Reclassification of Salaries (Govt. Printing Office), 1921 (Box 2)
      - Will Prices Drop to Pre-War Levels? ( Rev. of Reviews ), 1921 (Box 2)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1921 (Box 2)
      - Letter re Over-Abundance of Gold ( Tribune, Salt Lake City, Utah), 1921 (Box 2)
    - Causes of the high cost of living
      - The Monetary Side of the Cost of Living Problem ( Annals of Amer. Acad. of Polit. & Social Sciences ), 1913 (Box 2)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1913 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same ( Financial America ), 1913 (Box 2)
        - Extract from same ( Examiner, Chicago), 1913 (Box 2)
      - Note on Professor Ashley's Cost of Living", 1913 (Box 2)
      - Address to Hartford Twentieth Century Club ( Times, Hartford), 1913 (Box 2)
      - Letter on M. Thery's Study of Paper Money and Its Effect upon Prices ( Market World and Chronicle ), 1914 (Box 2)
      - Extract from "Why is the Dollar Shrinking?" ( Public Ledger, Phila.), 1914 (Box 2)
      - Our Yellow Peril ( The Financier ), 1917 (Box 2)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1917 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same ( Moody's Magazine ), 1917 (Box 2)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1917 (Box 2)
      - Article Based on "Our Yellow Peril" ( Public Ledger, Phil.), 1917 (Box 2)
      - Address before Outlook Club of Montclair based on "Our Yellow Peril" ( Montclair Times ), 1917 (Box 2)
      - Extract from "Our Yellow Peril" ( Goodbody Market Letter ), 1917 (Box 2)
        - Extract from same
          - Gazette, Colorado Springs Col., 1917 (Box 2)
          - Journal, Lansing, Mich., 1917 (Box 2)
          - Literary Digest, 1917 (Box 2)
          - World Herald, Omaha, 1917 (Box 2)
      - Letter re Gold Production based on "Our Yellow Peril" ( N.Y. Times ), 1917 (Box 2)
      - Interview on Cause of H.C.L. ( N.Y. Globe ), 1921 (Box 2)
    - International Conference on the High Cost of Living
      - What an International Conference on the High Cost of Living Could Do ( Institut International de Statistique ), 1913 (Box 2)
      - Die Lebensmittelteurung und ihre Bekämpfung (Reclams Universum, Leipsig), 1913 (Box 2)
        - Broadside of same, 1913 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same ( Rostocker Anzeiger), 1913 (Box 2)
      - Observation et Stabilisation des Prix, communication à la Société de Statistique de Paris, 1913 (Box 2)
    - Wages and the high cost of living
      - Adjusting Wages to the Cost of Living ( Monthly Labor Review ), 1918 (Box 2)
        - Reprint of same, 1918 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same ( Trade Union News, Phila.), 1919 (Box 2)
        - Extracts from same ( Survey, N.Y.), 1919 (Box 2)
      - Shifting Wages with the Cost of Living ( Red Cross Magazine ), 1920 (Box 2)
      - Letter re use of index numbers for regulating wages ( Revista Economia Argentina ), 1920 (Box 2)
    - Publications contained in other forms in previous volumes
      - Extract from "Instability of Gold" ( News, Elgin, Ill.), 1913 (Box 2)
    - Early publications omitted from previous volumes
      - Extract from address before City Club, St. Louis ( St. Louis Republic ), 1911 (Box 2)
      - Die Internationale Untersuchung über die Teuerung ( Die Konjunktur, Berlin), 1912 (Box 2)
  - Economic Essays, Vol. IX: "Stabilizing the Dollar", 1913 June 1 - 1919 January 1
    - General publications
      - Coué Defended ( Journal-Courier, New Haven, Ct.), 1923 Jan 30, 1913 (Box 3)
      - La Hausse Actuelle de la Monnaie du Credit et de Prix Revue D'Economie Politique ), 1913 (Box 3)
      - Address before Massachusetts Bankers at Nantasket ( United States Investor, Boston), 1913 (Box 3)
      - The Compensated Dollar and the Gold Yield ( Mining Science ), 1913 (Box 3)
      - Series of articles written for Chamber of Commerce News, Boston, 1913 (Box 3)
        - 1. The Present Inflation of Money, Credit and Prices, 1913 (Box 3)
        - 2. The Outlook for the Future Level of Prices, 1913 (Box 3)
        - 3. The Evils of Price Fluctuations, 1913 (Box 3)
        - 4. The Proposed Remedy: The Standardized Dollar, 1913 (Box 3)
        - Reprint of first half of No. 1 above, 1913 (Box 3)
      - Objections to a Compensated Dollar Answered (reprinted from American Economic Rev. ), 1914 (Box 3)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1914 (Box 3)
      - High Cost of Living and Standardizing the Dollar, address before Canadian Club, Toronto ( Proceedings of the Canadian Club ), 1914 (Box 3)
        - Extracts from same ( Toronto Daily News ), 1914 (Box 3)
      - The Standardization of the Dollar, address before Cleveland Chamber of Commerce, 1914 (Box 3)
        - Extracts from same ( Call, Newark, N.J.), 1914 (Box 3)
      - Extracts from address before City Lunch Club of Rochester ( Times, Rochester), 1914 (Box 3)
        - Extracts from same ( Union andAdvertiser, Rochester, N.Y.), 1914 (Box 3)
        - Extracts from same ( Post-Express, Rochester), 1914 (Box 3)
      - The Dollar Depreciating ( Yale News ), 1915 (Box 3)
        - Reprint of same ( North American, Phila.), 1915 (Box 3)
      - Letter concerning Editorial in Post re $ plan ( Post, Louisville, Ky.), 1915 (Box 3)
      - Abstracts from "Objections to a Compensated Dollar Answered" ( Moody's Magazine ), 1915 (Box 3)
      - Extracts from speech before Economic Club of New York ( Evening Sun, N.Y. ), 1917 (Box 3)
      - Hitchcock Lectures on Price Movements delivered at University of California, broadsides of each lecture sent out by Associated Press, 1917 (Box 3)
        - 1. Price Movements Before the Great War (broadside), 1917 (Box 3)
          - Reprint ( Public Ledger ), 1917 (Box 3)
        - 2. Price Movements During the War (broadside), 1917 (Box 3)
          - Reprint ( Public Ledger ), 1917 (Box 3)
        - 3. Inflation to Blame (broadside), 1917 (Box 3)
          - Reprint ( Public Ledger ), 1917 (Box 3)
        - 4. Evils of Price Movements (broadside), 1917 (Box 3)
          - Reprint ( Public Ledger ), 1917 (Box 3)
        - 5. Remedies (broadside), 1917 (Box 3)
          - Reprint ( Public Ledger ), 1917 (Box 3)
        - 6. Standardizing the Dollar (broadside), 1917 (Box 3)
          - Reprint ( Public Ledger ), 1917 (Box 3)
          - Reprint ( University of California Chron. ), 1917 (Box 3)
          - Separate reprint from above, 1917 (Box 3)
      - Abstract of address before Commercial Club, San Francisco ( Bulletin, San Francisco), 1917 (Box 3)
      - Can the Purchasing Power of the Dollar be Controlled?, address at Reed College, Portland ( Evening Telegram, Portland), 1917 (Box 3)